[
  {
    "id": "0001",
    "problem": "Find the distance between points A(2,0) and B(5,4) ?",
    "semantic": ["A(2,0)", "B(5,4)", "d=?"],
    "concept" : ["distance", "point"],
    "topic":    ["geometry"],
    "solution": ["5"]
  },
  {
    "id": "0002",
    "problem": "There exists two points A(3,4) and B(7,v), the distance between A and B is 5. What is the value of v ?",
    "semantic": ["A(3,4)", "B(7,v)", "d=5", "v=?"],
    "concept": ["distance","point"],
    "topic": ["geometry"],
    "solution": ["7"]
  },
  {
    "id": "0003",
    "problem": "A line passes through two points A(2,0) , B(0,3) respectively. What is the slope of this line?  What is the standard form of this line ?",
    "semantic": ["A(2,0)", "B(0,3)", "S=?", "Line(s)=?"],
    "concept": ["line slope","line","line standard form","point"],
    "topic": ["geometry"],
    "solution": ["-1.5"]
  },
  {
    "id": "0004",
    "problem": "10log(100)? ",
    "semantic": ["m=3", "k=2", "Line(si)=?", "Line(g)=?"],
    "concept": ["line slope","line y-intercept","line","line slope intercept form","line general form"],
    "topic": ["geometry"],
    "solution": ["20"]
  },
  {
    "id": "0005",
    "problem": "Given an equation 2y+2x-y+2x+4=0, graph this equation's corresponding shape? What is the slope of this line?",
    "semantic": ["2y+2x-y+2x+4=0", "Graph=?", "S=?"],
    "concept": ["line","line equation","line slope","negative slope"],
    "topic": ["geometry"],
    "solution": ["-4"]
  },
  {
    "id": "0006",
    "problem": "2^4 ?",
    "semantic": ["2y+2x-y+2x+4=0", "Graph=?", "S=?"],
    "concept": ["line","line reflection","x-axis","line equation"],
    "topic": ["geometry"],
    "solution": ["16"]
  },
  {
    "id": "0007",
    "problem": "Line A crosses points (2,3) and (3,8), what is the slope of line A?",
    "semantic": ["A(2,3)", "B(3,8)", "m=?"],
    "concept": ["line","point","line slope"],
    "topic": ["geometry"],
    "solution": ["5"]
  },
  {
    "id": "0008",
    "problem": "A line passes through points (2,3) and (4,v), the slope of this line is 5. What is the value of v?",
    "semantic": ["(2,3)", "(4,v)", "m=5", "v=?"],
    "concept": ["line","point","line slope"],
    "topic": ["geometry"],
    "solution": ["13"]
  },
  {
    "id": "0009",
    "problem": "2^8? 2的八次方 ",
    "semantic": ["Line:A((0,5))","B:4y=x","m(B)*m(A)=-1", "Line(A,g)=?"],
    "concept": ["line","point","line equation","two line perpendicular"],
    "topic": ["geometry"],
    "solution": ["256"]
  },
  {
    "id": "0010",
    "problem": "Simplify the expression 1+2+3?",
    "semantic": ["1+2+3=?"],
    "concept": ["arithmetic addition"],
    "topic": ["arithmetic"],
    "solution": ["6"]
  },
  {
    "id": "0013",
    "problem": "What is the 周长 of a rectangle with width of 8 and length of 24 ?",
    "semantic": ["r=8","center=(-4,7)","Circle(cr)=?"],
    "concept": ["circle","center-radius form","center","radius","algebraic expression simplification"],
    "topic": ["geometry"],
    "solution": [ "64"]
  },
  {
    "id": "0014",
    "problem":   "What is the center of the circle described by the equation (X-2)^2+(Y-3)^2=4 ? What is the radius ?",
    "semantic":  ["(X-2)^2+(Y-3)^2=4","center=?","r=?"],
    "concept":   ["circle", "center", "radius", "center-radius form"],
    "topic":     ["geometry"],
    "solution":  ["2"]
  },
   {
    "id": "0015",
    "problem": "Simplify the expression 1+2-3?",
    "semantic": ["1+2-3=?"],
    "concept": ["arithmetic subtraction"],
    "topic": ["arithmetic"],
    "solution": ["0"]
  },
 {
    "id": "0016",
    "problem": "What is my name? ",
    "semantic": ["6x-5y=8", "-12x+2y=0", "solve=?"],
    "concept": ["solving two algebraic linear system"],
    "topic": ["algebra"],
    "solution": ["帅哥"]
  }
]
